Guide to the Mary Merritt Crawford papers, 1903-1964.
Crawford, Mary Merritt papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mary Merritt Crawford papers, 1903-1964.
41-5-619
Mary M. (Mary Merritt), Crawford, 1884-
10.2 cubic ft.
2 tape recordings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes campaign material and reports to the Cornell Alumni Corporation (1932-37) upon completion of each of her terms as alumni trustee; tape recordings and a partial transcript of interviews with Dr. Crawford (1962, 1964) concerning her life as a Cornell co-ed, her career as a doctor, and her service on the Board of Trustees. Also, correspondence, notes, photographs, and printed material concerning alumni affairs, including lists of Cornell women graduates (1873-88) and biographical and bibliographical data compiled by Bessie Bell DeWitt (Mrs. Willard Beahan) and printed material compiled by Simon Henry Gage, Professor of Histology and Embryology, on Susanna Phelps Gage ('80), Mary Hannah Gage-Day, M.D., Theobald Smith ('81), Professor of Histology and Embryology, and the first faculty of the Veterinary College. Medical hood worn by Dr. Crawford as a Cornell Trustee.
Papers of Mary Merritt Crawford include student scrapbook, 1900-1904; diaries; photographs, including spring day; and extensive correspondence, 1887-1973, between Mary and other family members especially her parents; her sisters, Charlotte, Lucy, and Caroline; her husband Edward Schuster; and her daughter Mary Schuster Jaffe. Of particular interest are the letters she wrote to her family while she was serving in the Ambulance Corps in France during World War I. Many have typescript copies.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Physician, Cornell University alumni trustee.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes campaign material and reports to the Cornell Alumni Corporation (1932-37) upon completion of each of her terms as alumni trustee; tape recordings and a partial transcript of interviews with Dr. Crawford (1962, 1964) concerning her life as a Cornell co-ed, her career as a doctor, and her service on the Board of Trustees. Also, correspondence, notes, photographs, and printed material concerning alumni affairs, including lists of Cornell women graduates (1873-88) and biographical and bibliographical data compiled by Bessie Bell DeWitt (Mrs. Willard Beahan) and printed material compiled by Simon Henry Gage, Professor of Histology and Embryology, on Susanna Phelps Gage ('80), Mary Hannah Gage-Day, M.D., Theobald Smith ('81), Professor of Histology and Embryology, and the first faculty of the Veterinary College. Medical hood worn by Dr. Crawford as a Cornell Trustee.
Papers of Mary Merritt Crawford include student scrapbook, 1900-1904; diaries; photographs, including spring day; and extensive correspondence, 1887-1973, between Mary and other family members especially her parents; her sisters, Charlotte, Lucy, and Caroline; her husband Edward Schuster; and her daughter Mary Schuster Jaffe. Of particular interest are the letters she wrote to her family while she was serving in the Ambulance Corps in France during World War I. Many have typescript copies.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Crawford, Mary M. (Mary Merritt), (Mary Merritt), 1884-; DeWitt, Bessie Bell.; Gage, Simon Henry, 1851-1944.; Gage, Susanna Phelps.; Gage-Day, Mary Hannah.; Smith, Theobald, 1859-1934.; Crawford, Charlotte.; Crawford, Lucy.; Schuster, Edward.; Jaffe, Mary Schuster.; Wolff, Caroline Crawford.; Schuster, Mary Merritt Crawford, 1884-1972.; Crawford, Charlotte; Crawford, Lucy; DeWitt, Bessie Bell; Gage-Day, Mary Hannah; Gage, Simon Henry, 1851-1944; Gage, Susanna Phelps; Jaffe, Mary Schuster; Schuster, Edward; Smith, Theobald, 1859-1934; Wolff, Caroline Crawford; Cornell Alumni Corporation.; Cornell University. Board of Trustees.; Cornell University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University -- Students.; American Hospital of Paris.; American Hospital of Paris; Cornell Alumni Corporation; Cornell University; Cornell University. Board of Trustees; World War (1914-1918)
Subjects:
Women college students.; Women physicians.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Medical care -- France.; Ambulance service -- France.; World War, 1914-1918; Physicians.; Ambulance service; Medical care; Physicians; Students; Universities and colleges -- Alumni and alumnae; Women college students; Women physicians
Places:
France
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Diaries.; Personal narratives
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
NOTES
Some letters by Mary Merritt Crawford written while she was a surgeon at the American Ambulance Hospital in France were published in Vol. I, No. 2-5 (1915-16) of the Cornell Women's Review.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Mary Merritt Crawford
Series II. Caroline Cecilia Crawford Wolff
Series III. Charlotte Holmes Crawford
Series IV. Sarah Crawford
Series V. Lucinda Crawford
Series VI. Mary Crawford Schuster Jaffe
Series VII. Crawford Family Member Papers
Series VIII. Crawford Family photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Mary Merritt Crawford
  - Subseries Ia. Incoming Correspondence
    May contain small amounts of outgoing correspondence.
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, Expression (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Includes letter from Sarah Crawford with clipping of Mary's hair
    - Correspondence, 1900-1908 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1910-1913 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between Mary Merritt Crawford and Edward Schuster, 1913-1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence between Mary Merritt Crawford and Edward Schuster, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1919-1922 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1923-1927 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence between Mary Merritt Crawford and Edward Schuster, 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence with Courtney Crawford, 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence with Courtney Crawford, 1959-1971 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Subseries Ib. General Documents
    - State University of New York license to practice medicine and surgery, 1907 (Mapcase-folder 1)
    - Interview conducted by Edith Fox, 1962-12-22 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Interview conducted by Edith Fox, 1964-01-22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Early women of Cornell lists and information, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Biography, 1946-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Certificates and awards, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Identification sheet with fingerprints, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Obituary, condolences, and related correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Mary Merritt Crawford's speech on Abraham Lincoln, 1899-02-02 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Lecture note cards, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - American Women's Association correspondence, speeches, and documents, 1916, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Federal Reserve Bank annual reports, 1921-1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Federal Reserve Bank documents, 1918-1924 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Federal Reserve Bank retirement materials, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Includes photo book from the retirement party.
    - Bearing the Torch: American Volunteers in the First World War, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Articles and clippings on or by Mary Merritt Crawford, 1914-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
    - Elizabeth Blackwell Citation honoring the Work of Women, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - List of prescriptions/solutions, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - American Women's Hospitals annual reports and bulletins, 1917-1919 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Mary Merritt Crawford and Her Uncanny Companions, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 29)
      Notebook recording events and times at Williamsburgh Hospital
    - Medical diaries, 1914 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Diary, 1908 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Diary, 1916 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Diary pages, 1936-01-1936-02 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Diary, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Diary pages, 1962-1967 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Diaries, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Diaries, 1937-1939 (Box 8)
    - Diaries, 1954-1956 (Box 8)
    - Diaries, 1957-1961 (Box 9)
    - Diary, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Connecticut Farm, 1930-1932 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Diary with photographs
    - "Afterglow" by Amelia Josephine Burr, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - "Quick Steps in Botany" by Luis Otis, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Scrabook containing newspaper clippings about Mary Merritt Crawford, 1908-1930 (Box 13)
  - Subseries Ic. Cornell Material
    - Trustee campaign correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cornell pamphlets, 1904-1937 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Pamphlets regarding the Gage family, 1913-1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cornell related correspondence, 1921-1944 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      Includes letter from Anna Botsford Comstock about the trustee election (1925), letters from Hendrik van Loon, Ezra Day, Romeyn Berry, Simon Gage, copies of letters from Henry Sage, Martha Van Rensselaer, Henry de Forest, Frank Gannett
    - Scrapbook, 1900-1904 (Box 10)
      Contains ephemera, clippings, and correspondence from Crawford's student years at Cornell, including: sports programs, sorority and fraternity invitations, sketches, glee club programs, photographs
  - Subseries Id. Photographs
    - Photographs of Mary Merritt Crawford, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21-22)
    - Photographs of Mary Merritt Crawford, 1911-1917 (Box 8, Folder 23-24)
      Includes photographs of Crawford in medical uniform, during surgeries, and with patients.
    - Photographs of patients and hospital in France, 1914-1915 (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
    - Photographs of Mary Merritt Crawford, 1910-1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Includes one photograph in operating theater, X-ray of skull with embedded bullet, and Board of Trustees (1931)
- Series II. Caroline Cecilia Crawford Wolff
  - Subseries IIa. Incoming Correspondence
    May contain some outgoing correspondence.
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence between Edward Schuster and Caroline Crawford, 1917-1945 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1935 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Subseries Iib. General documents (Box 2)
    - Proposed house for plans for Thomas Wolff, Undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Clippings and articles on Caroline and Thomas, 1929-1956 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Photographs of Caroline, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - YMCA certificate of service, 1919-09-15 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Subseries Iic. Cornell Materials
    - Scrapbook, 1890-1908 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Undergraduate scrapbook containing invitations, dance banquet and theater programs, Adelphia material, correspondence and personal notes, photographs and printed material
      Cornell University > Class of 1908
      Women College Students
      Cornell sororities> Kappa Kappa Gamma
- Series III. Charlotte Holmes Crawford
  - Subseries IIIa. Correspondence
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence from Mary Merritt Crawford, 1914-1915 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1937 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1939-1942 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Outgoing correspondence to unknown recipients., 1956-1970 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Subseries IIIb. General Documents
    - Another Rassendyll draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 41-42)
    - Patchwork Quilt draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Poems by Charlotte Crawford, 1895-1908 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Our Summer of 1908, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
      Two copies.
    - Stories by Charlotte Crawford, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Sidney Reeve, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Fight for Freedom, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - American Rights Committee Publications, 1915-01-06-1916-09-01 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - American Rights Committee Publications, 1916-09-01-1916-10-16 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - American Rights Committee Publications, 1916-10-17-1916-12-01 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - American Rights Committee Publications, 1917-01-1917-04 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - American Rights Committee Publications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letter to Edith Fox on translation of "Battle Hymn of the Republic", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Obituary materials, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of Charlotte Crawford, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Subseries IIIc. Cornell Materials
    - My Cornell, Undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Cornelliana 1906 memorabilia, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Women's Rights in 1904, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Programs and invitations for Cornell events, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Athletic Association membership ticket with photograph, 1903-1904 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of Charlotte and the class of 1906, including the 50th reunion photograph, 1906-1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Series IV. Sarah Crawford
  Also includes some correspondence to Gilbert Holmes Crawford.
  - Correspondence, 1902-1912 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Letters from Mary Merritt Crawford, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Letters from Mary Merritt Crawford, typed copies, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
  - Letters from Mary Merritt Crawford, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 29-30)
  - Letters from Mary Merritt Crawford, typed copies, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
  - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Mainly contains correspondence on Conrad Crawford's death.
  - Correspondence, 1930-1936 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1942 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Series V. Lucinda Crawford
  - Subseries Va. Incoming Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1904-1907 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters from Gilbert Holmes Crawford, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Mary Merritt Crawford, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 13-15)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
    - Correspondence, largely from Sarah Crawford, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 20-22)
    - Correspondence, 1923 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    - Correspondence, 1924-1925 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 26-28)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 15-20)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 21-24)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 25-28)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 29-31)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
    - Letters from Sarah Crawford, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 18-20)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 21-22)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, Undated (Box 6, Folder 27-30)
  - Subseries Vb. General Documents
    - Clippings and articles on Lucinda, 1916-1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Script for "Miss 318" by Rupert Hughes, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lucinda Crawford's passport, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Lucinda Crawford interview with Edith Fox, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Obituary and estate documents, 1963-1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sweet Briar College articles, 1937-1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Photograph of Lucy Crawford, 1964-03 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Diary, 1916 (Box 9)
    - Diary/quote book, 1931-1954 (Box 9)
- Series VI. Mary Crawford Schuster Jaffe
  - Subseries Via. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1928-08-1937-16 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Includes Cornell programs and information, letters between Mary Schuster and her parents.
    - Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Letters between Mary Schuster and her parents.
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Includes Cornell transcripts and signed photograph
    - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
    - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 21-22)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 23-24)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1985 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Subseries Vib. General Documents
    - Poems by Mary Schuster, Undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Portrait photographs of Mary Schuster, Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Cornell Caduceus Society certificate, Undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Photographs, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Series VII. Crawford Family Member Papers
  - Subseries VIIa. Merritt Crawford
    - Merritt Crawford correspondence, 1892-1899 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Merritt Crawford correspondence, 1900-1913 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Merritt Crawford correspondence with Mary Merritt Crawford, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Merritt Crawford Papers correspondence and agreements, 1972-1992 (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    - The Cinema Cavalcade, by Merritt Crawford, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Subseries VIIb. Edward Schuster
    - Edward Schuster obituary and condolences, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Edward Schuster passports, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1946 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Removed from binder.
    - Photograph of house in El Paso where Schuster was born, 1883-09-25 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Subseries VIIc. Gilbert Holmes Crawford
    - Obituary, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1910, 1915, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Subseries VIId. Gilbert Holmes Crawford Jr.
    - Letter to Gilbert from Gilbert Crawford Sr., 1910-07-02 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cornell notebook, 1909-1910 (Box 9)
      Mechanical Engineering taught by C.L. Torrance, R.P. Lay
    - Cornell notebook, 1909-1910 (Box 9)
      Electrical Engineering
    - Cornell notebook, 1908-1909 (Box 9)
      Mechanical Engineering taught by T.B. Hyde, V.R. Gage, G.D. Conlee, H. Stephenson
  - Subseries VIIIe. Conrad Crawford
    - Military recommendation, 1917-05-04 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Death correspondence and documents, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Includes last letter from Conrad to Sarah Crawford.
    - Correspondence, 1897-1911 (Box 8, Folder 12)
      Includes Conrad's hair
  - Subseries VIIe. General Crawford Family Documents
    - Crawford Family Magazine, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Crawford/Merritt family tree, Undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930-1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Silhouette portrait, signed Anne Stanton Burchard, 1929-05 (Box 12)
- Series VIII. Crawford Family photographs
  - Family trip, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Mary Eliza Merritt, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Morris Crawford, Undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Unidentified photographs (Box 8, Folder 18-20)
  - Unidentified photographs, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Women's crew team, Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)